ANDREW PUTILOV

to.merge@gmail.com LinkedIn: andrew-putilov Github: m8rge

Saint Petersburg, Russia UTC+2

Summary

10+ years of experience in building web applications both from scratch and diving into an existing codebase.

Currently, I'm an infrastructure developer (Golang) in the Yandex team.

At my current place, I developed and support a logs delivery system with 400k+ messages per second and a 600MB/s+ data rate.

Another project I can highlight is the WMS system with topology editing. I developed this system and implemented it at the warehouse from scratch that allows collecting items faster and made inventory transparent.

Experience

Infrastructure developer, Yandex; Russia — 2019–Present Logs delivery and view system, team of 12:

- Reduced memory usage by 50% by replacing json parsing library
- Increased stability by implementing buffer limits
- Pushed gRPC plugin archive storage support to jaeger github repository
- Developed typescript plugin for Grafana from scratch, it allows to view and search logs
- Developed cli binary that allows viewing realtime streaming logs
- Developed unified (both Grafana plugin and cli) query language using grammar parser

Deploy system, team of 12:

- Improved user error reporting
- Reduced unnecessary errors

Technologies: go, typescript, nomad, jaeger, grafana, gprc, sentry, docker, logbroker, telegram, zookeeper, postgres, clickhouse.

Freelance web developer, Aspire Worldwide; Remote — 2015–2020 Internal backend of aspireww.com, team of 3:

- Introduced docker in deploy process, migrated all codebase to a docker image
- Developed simple mobile-first check-in
- Refactored internal sections and reports to be effective and simple
- Improved billing system

Technologies: php, yii2, mysql, jquery, html, css, docker.

Tech lead developer, Boxberry.ru; Russia — 2018–2019 Internal backend of boxberry.ru, team of 6:

- Developed new architecture for storing and fetching parcels data
- Introduced code tests, code coverage increased up to 30%
- Increased system stability by introducing crucial components such as circuit breaker and api rate limiter
- Increased code quality by using linters and performing code review

Technologies: go, mongodb, docker, yii2, go, mysql, jquery, html, css, redis, gitlab, rabbitmq.

Web developer, <u>E96.ru</u>; Russia — 2014–2018 Warehouse management system, team of 3:

- Developed and implemented WMS at the warehouse. Worker's shortest walk path calculated using warehouse topology
- Developed mobile application for portable data terminal

Technologies: php, yii2, mysql, neo4j, c#, jquery, html, css, docker, redis.

Web developer, <u>66.ru</u>; Russia — 2009–2014 City website, team of 7:

- Developed new website sections: car selection by various attributes and "yellow pages" section
- Developed and supported a new website engine for 66.ru and ekabu.ru

Technologies: php, yii2, mysql, jquery, html, css.

Education

USTU-UPI, Yekaterinburg, Russia - 2004-2009

Skills

Proficient: go, linux, networks, docker, kafka, zookeeper, php, mysql, rabbitmq, yii2, test automation, code review, Cl/CD, micro-services Knowledgable: react-native, symfony, html, neo4j, es5, c#, c99, c++

Some familiarity: node.js, typescript, electron, objective c, phalcon framework